Предназначение рекуррентных диаграмм (RP) дать зрительный анализ траекторий в фазовых пространствах.
Внешний вид диаграммы дает представление об эволюции этих траекторий во времени.
Фазовый портрет системы (PhS) дает другой вид поведения рассматриваемой системы.
Cовместный анализ RP и PhS позволяет выявить новые свойства системы.
Использование RP для анализа временного ряда, дает возможность определить его подобие имеющимся
RP в данной базе - галерее. 
Такая возможность позволяет выбрать математическую модель, соответствующую выбранной RP.
Затем требуется выполнить параметрическую идентификацию, на основе реальных данных.
Если подобной RP не удается найти, а математическая модель реального процесса требуется для анализа, 
прогнозирования, управления процессом, необходимо обращаться к специалистам.
Возможности ИТ-фирм в решении данной проблемы ограничены.
Отметим, что в работе были использованы основные модельные системы, представленные
в следующих работах:

The purpose of Recurrence Plots (RP) is to give a visual analysis of trajectories in phase spaces.
The appearance of the RP gives an idea of ​​the evolution of these trajectories in time.
The phase portrait of the system (PhS) gives another kind of behavior of the system under consideration.
A joint analysis of RP and PhS allows us to reveal new properties of the system.
The use of RP for time series analysis makes it possible to determine its similarity by the available
RP in this database - gallery.
This feature allows you to select the mathematical model corresponding to the selected RP.
Then you need to perform parametric identification, based on real data.
If such an RP can not be found, and the mathematical model of a real process is required for analysis,
forecasting, process management, it is necessary to contact specialists.
The capabilities of IT firms in solving this problem are limited.
We note that the main model systems in the following works:

1. Wang X., Chen G.  A Gallery of Lorenz-like and Chen-like attractors // International Journal of Bifurcation 
and Chaos, Vol. 23, No. 4 (2013) 1330011 (20 pages).
2. Belozyorov V.Ye., ZaytsevV.G. Recurrence analysis of time series generated by 3D autonomous quadratic dynamical 
systems depending on parameters // Visnyk DNU, Series: Modeling:  – Dnipropetrovsk. – 2016. - 24(8), – P. 56-70.
3. Eckmann J.P., Kamphorst S.O., Ruelle D. Recurrence plots of dynamical systems // Europhysics Letters. 
1987. Vol. 5. P. 973–977.
4. Zbilut J. P., Webber Jr.C. L. Embeddings and delays as derived from quantification of recurrence
plots // Physics Letters A 171 (3–4). 1992. P. 199–203.
5. Marwan, N.  A Historical Review of Recurrence Plots // European Physical Journal  2008, V. 164: PP. 3–12.

Chirikov map. 
\begin{equation}
    \left\{
    \begin{array} {1}
        x_{n+1} = x_{n} + y_{n+1},\\
        y_{n+1} = y_{n} +p_{1}sin(x_{n}.\\
    \end{array}
    \right.    
\end{equation}
    
       $p_{1} = 0.7;  N = 1750;  y(1)=1.25; x(1) = 0.5$
       
Henon map with trigonometric nonlinearity.
\begin{equation}
    \left\{
    \begin{array} {1}
 x_{n+1} = -(y_{n}-x^{2}_{n})*sin(2Pi/p_{1})+x_{n}cos(2Pi/p_{1}),\\
 y_{n+1} = (y_{n}-x^{2}_{n})*cos(2Pi/p_{1})+x_{n}sin(2Pi/p_{1}).\\
    \end{array}
    \right.    
\end{equation}

$p_{1} = 5.6; N=550;  x(1) =0.04; y(1) = -0.6;$

Quadratic Henon mapping
\begin{equation}
    \left\{
    \begin{array} {1}
        x_{n+1} = y_{n} + 1 + p_{1}x^{2}_{n},\\
        y_{n+1} = p_{2}x_{n}.\\
    \end{array}
    \right.    
\end{equation}
$p_{1}= 5.6;  N=550;  x(1)=0.01; y(1)=0.05;$

$p_{1} = -1.4;  p_{2} = 0.3; tay = 11; x(1)=0.01; y(1)= 0.05$.
